<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Charles Lewer</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Charles Lewer</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:11:10 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>tick</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/tick/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:11:10 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/tick/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;BOOM&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Please Woman Don&#39;t Go</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/please-woman-dont-go/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 09:56:44 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/please-woman-dont-go/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Please Woman Don&amp;rsquo;t Go&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fuckit</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/fuckit/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:49:06 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/fuckit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;done it
seen it
heard about it
dreamt about it
done
over and out
blessed, cursed, loved, and misunderstood&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>West Lake: A National Model for Renewal</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/west-lake-a-national-model-for-renrenewal/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:26:03 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/west-lake-a-national-model-for-renrenewal/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;west-lake-a-national-model-for-renewal&#34;&gt;West Lake: A National Model for Renewal
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if the future we were promised—the one filled with progress, prosperity, and harmony with the Earth—didn’t lie in some far-off dream, but beneath our very feet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West Lake could be that future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No longer just a contaminated landfill, it becomes the flagship for a new American era. A place where innovation rises from our mistakes. Where healing the land becomes a source of power—literally. Where we stop hiding our failures and start transforming them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By investing in advanced nuclear technologies—molten salt reactors, modular energy systems, and on-site reprocessing—we do more than clean up waste. We launch Missouri into the global spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just cleanup. It’s cutting-edge infrastructure. It’s a smart energy grid powered by legacy waste. It’s a regenerative economy that fuels itself by working &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the environment. Every dollar spent has exponential returns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;public health&lt;/strong&gt;, as radiation exposure and related illnesses fall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;the environment&lt;/strong&gt;, as contaminated zones turn green again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;jobs and revenue&lt;/strong&gt;, as high-tech industries take root.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;education and innovation&lt;/strong&gt;, as students grow up with access to the world’s most exciting clean energy hub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how Missouri becomes a leader—not just in energy, but in vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bring the future home. And West Lake becomes a source of pride, not just for St. Louis, not just for Missouri—but for the world. A living example of what it looks like when a country takes responsibility, and turns it into opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We clean the mess we made—and from it, build the world we always hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to live in the future we were promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-history-and-hazards-of-the-west-lake-site&#34;&gt;The History and Hazards of the West Lake Site
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;West Lake Landfill, located in Bridgeton, Missouri, is the resting place of radioactive waste tied to the Manhattan Project—the United States’ top-secret effort to build the first atomic bomb. In the early 1970s, waste from uranium processing was mixed with soil and dumped into the landfill without liners, protective barriers, or clear public oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, this site became one of the nation’s most visible examples of environmental neglect—not because it was the worst, but because &lt;strong&gt;so little was done for so long&lt;/strong&gt;, even as risks mounted. Residents raised concerns. Cancer rates climbed. Yet the response was slow, fragmented, and opaque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.epa.gov/mo/west-lake-landfill&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EPA’s own records&lt;/a&gt; confirm, West Lake was declared a Superfund site in 1990. But decades later, the radioactive material still sits in the ground—exposed to the elements, and to the lives lived around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-its-a-problem&#34;&gt;Why It’s a Problem
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most urgent threat comes from a &lt;strong&gt;subsurface fire&lt;/strong&gt;—a smoldering underground reaction in the adjacent Bridgeton Landfill. Experts have confirmed that this fire is slowly migrating toward the radioactive zone. If it makes contact, it could release &lt;strong&gt;airborne radioactive particulates&lt;/strong&gt; into surrounding communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, contamination concerns have extended beyond the landfill. The nearby &lt;strong&gt;Coldwater Creek&lt;/strong&gt; area, which received runoff from similar WWII-era waste, has been linked to an unusually high incidence of rare cancers, autoimmune disorders, and birth defects (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://health.mo.gov&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Missouri Department of Health&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local families have lived with fear for decades. Some have moved. Others have buried loved ones. Many are still waiting for meaningful action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-risk-of-doing-nothing&#34;&gt;The Risk of Doing Nothing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cost of inaction is not just measured in dollars—it’s measured in health, trust, and time lost:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airborne risk&lt;/strong&gt;: An underground fire breaching the waste zone could release radioactive gases or dust into the air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groundwater contamination&lt;/strong&gt;: The waste sits near a major aquifer and watershed. Leaching could spread radioactive materials into the Missouri River system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Escalating costs&lt;/strong&gt;: The longer we wait, the harder—and more expensive—it becomes to solve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erosion of trust&lt;/strong&gt;: Each year that passes without resolution deepens public skepticism in government and industry alike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may not need to assign blame—but we do need to take responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news? We now have the tools, the science, and the opportunity to make it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;global-reclamation-models-proof-it-can-be-done&#34;&gt;Global Reclamation Models: Proof It Can Be Done
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transforming nuclear‑contaminated sites into safe, useful spaces isn’t hypothetical—it’s been happening for decades around the world. Here&amp;rsquo;s how those models can guide Missouri’s future:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-france--recycling-and-reuse-since-1976&#34;&gt;🇫🇷 France – Recycling and Reuse (since 1976)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;France has operated reprocessing plants at La Hague since 1976. To date, over &lt;strong&gt;34,000 metric tons&lt;/strong&gt; of spent fuel have been processed, and &lt;strong&gt;95%&lt;/strong&gt; of it is recycled into new reactor material 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missouri Connection:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
West Lake contains uranium-rich material that could be similarly recovered and reused locally. Over time, the reprocessing facility can pay for itself through energy generation—just as France has demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-japan--fukushima-recovery-since-2011&#34;&gt;🇯🇵 Japan – Fukushima Recovery (since 2011)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cleanup began immediately after the March 2011 disaster. Automated cooling systems were installed within three months, and by December of the same year, reactors were in cold shutdown 2. As of 2020, $27 billion has been spent, radiation in key areas reduced by over &lt;strong&gt;70%&lt;/strong&gt;, and towns have begun repopulating 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missouri Connection:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
West Lake faces similar challenges—community fear, soil contamination, long-term cleanup. Fukushimas’ phased recovery shows that with sustained investment and data-driven monitoring, population return and environmental restoration are possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-germany--decommissioning-with-care-asse-ii-1967present&#34;&gt;🇩🇪 Germany – Decommissioning with Care (Asse II, 1967–present)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From 1967 to 1978, around &lt;strong&gt;47,000 m³&lt;/strong&gt; of low- and intermediate‑level waste was stored underground at Asse II 4. Today, authorities have begun retrieval efforts, with public oversight and geological safety controls in place 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missouri Connection:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Like Asse II, West Lake has buried radioactive material in unstable conditions (an underground fire, in this case). Germany’s experience demonstrates that retrieval—though challenging—is the responsible path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-sweden--trusted-local-storage-since-1988&#34;&gt;🇸🇪 Sweden – Trusted, Local Storage (since 1988)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sweden’s SFR underground repository has operated since 1988, handling &lt;strong&gt;600 m³&lt;/strong&gt; of low‑ and intermediate‑level waste and receiving about 600 m³ each year 6. Crucially, local decision-making and public consultation built strong trust 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missouri Connection:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Community buy-in is crucial. As in Sweden, empowering local voices alongside transparent monitoring will make a future West Lake facility more acceptable and resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These international examples show that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleanup and reprocessing work on a national scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term investment yields measurable improvements—reduced contamination, repopulation, public trust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When science, transparency, and partnership align, toxic legacies become sources of value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missouri doesn’t need to reinvent the wheel—it can adopt proven models and tailor them locally. The result? A clean, confident, and forward‑looking community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-it-makes-sense-to-reprocess-locally&#34;&gt;Why It Makes Sense to Reprocess Locally
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The radioactive waste buried at West Lake isn’t just a threat—it’s also a resource. Buried within that contaminated soil is &lt;strong&gt;uranium&lt;/strong&gt;, a material with real economic and energy value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-hidden-asset-not-just-a-liability&#34;&gt;A Hidden Asset, Not Just a Liability
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uranium is the fuel that powers nuclear reactors around the world. Even low-enriched uranium—like what’s found in the West Lake Landfill—can be reprocessed and reused in &lt;strong&gt;advanced reactor systems&lt;/strong&gt;, including molten salt reactors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach mirrors the core principle of &lt;strong&gt;conservation of energy&lt;/strong&gt;: energy can’t be destroyed, only transformed. Rather than sealing this potential away forever or shipping it off to burden another community, we embrace it—&lt;strong&gt;transforming a legacy of harm into a source of healing and progress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uranium price per lb (2024):&lt;/strong&gt; ~$90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hundreds of tons&lt;/strong&gt; of uranium-contaminated soil are present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reclaimed material can be used to power &lt;strong&gt;modular reactors&lt;/strong&gt; that supply clean energy to Missouri for decades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of spending millions to discard it—we can use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-danger-of-moving-it&#34;&gt;The Danger of Moving It
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transporting radioactive waste is dangerous, expensive, and logistically unsound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The U.S. has over &lt;strong&gt;13.5 million large trucks&lt;/strong&gt; on the road each year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trucks account for &lt;strong&gt;9% of all fatal crashes&lt;/strong&gt;, despite being only ~4% of registered vehicles (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nhtsa.gov/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NHTSA&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missouri highways are &lt;strong&gt;already over capacity&lt;/strong&gt;, especially in the St. Louis region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding &lt;strong&gt;convoys of nuclear waste trucks&lt;/strong&gt; to already congested highways introduces unacceptable risk. One accident—whether a collision, spill, or even a mechanical failure—could trigger catastrophe or mass panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if the waste is moved safely…&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Where would it go?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Whose land would we risk next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t need to pass the problem on. We need to own the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;financial-sense-meets-moral-responsibility&#34;&gt;Financial Sense Meets Moral Responsibility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hauling radioactive waste across the country would cost &lt;strong&gt;hundreds of millions of dollars&lt;/strong&gt;—just in transport and shielding. That same investment could fund a &lt;strong&gt;local reprocessing and clean energy facility&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built adjacent to the existing site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed to handle and neutralize the exact waste present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staffed and operated by trained Missourians&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feeding energy directly into the grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It keeps the risk contained—and turns it into &lt;em&gt;return&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-missouri-opportunity&#34;&gt;The Missouri Opportunity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just a fix—it’s a future. A facility like this would spark growth across sectors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Projected Impact&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permanent jobs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;300–500+ (reactor ops, lab techs, engineers)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Construction-phase jobs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1,000+ (skilled labor, contracting, materials)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support industries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Fabrication, shielding, HVAC, clean-tech, security&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STEM &amp;amp; trades education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Partnerships with Missouri universities, trade schools&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spillover innovation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;R&amp;amp;D, robotics, energy storage, AI monitoring&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-term local revenue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Clean energy generation, federal matching grants, job tax base&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren&amp;rsquo;t just jobs—they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;strong&gt;careers in a future-facing economy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what it looks like to take responsibility for our past while building prosperity for generations to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t outsource the burden.&lt;br&gt;
We transform it into leadership.&lt;br&gt;
That’s conservation—in every sense of the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-west-lake-opportunity&#34;&gt;The West Lake Opportunity
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if the site that once symbolized environmental failure became the place that redefined environmental leadership?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West Lake isn’t just a cleanup site. It’s a chance to lead the nation in turning radioactive legacy waste into &lt;strong&gt;clean energy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;job creation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;public health improvements&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;restored trust&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more than a fix—it’s a future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-state-that-leads&#34;&gt;A State That Leads
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Missouri has always stood at the crossroads of America. Now, we stand at a crossroad in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By investing in advanced nuclear reclamation right here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We &lt;strong&gt;keep the economic benefit in-state&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We &lt;strong&gt;pioneer a new kind of infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;—smart, modular, and regenerative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We &lt;strong&gt;show the nation&lt;/strong&gt; that progress doesn’t mean abandoning the past—it means transforming it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This becomes a place others look to.&lt;br&gt;
West Lake becomes our &lt;strong&gt;proof of concept&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Our pride.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-healthier-missouri&#34;&gt;A Healthier Missouri
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ripple effects of restoring West Lake extend far beyond the fence line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced cancer and illness rates&lt;/strong&gt; in nearby communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleaner air and water&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fewer toxins passed to future generations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relieved pressure on local healthcare systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By healing the land, we help people live longer, healthier lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-economic-engine&#34;&gt;A New Economic Engine
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a temporary construction site—it’s a long-term opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We create:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permanent high-paying jobs&lt;/strong&gt; in nuclear tech, science, logistics, security, and clean energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support industries&lt;/strong&gt; in fabrication, shielding, sensors, automation, and robotics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training programs&lt;/strong&gt; and university partnerships that put young Missourians into future-proof careers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we spark new businesses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced manufacturing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery storage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-driven safety monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart energy grid tech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t just clean up—we &lt;em&gt;build up&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-story-worth-sharing&#34;&gt;A Story Worth Sharing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most places bury their mistakes and hope the public forgets.&lt;br&gt;
We can be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can own the story:&lt;br&gt;
➡ From Cold War byproduct to climate-era solution&lt;br&gt;
➡ From public neglect to public health&lt;br&gt;
➡ From poisoned ground to pioneering ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-success-looks-like&#34;&gt;What Success Looks Like
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean land, safe neighborhoods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affordable energy from reclaimed fuel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National headlines about innovation, not tragedy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students from around the world studying what we built&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local families proud to say:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“That used to be a problem. Now it’s our solution.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the West Lake opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s rise to meet it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;could-the-site-be-declared-a-disaster-to-garner-emergency-funding&#34;&gt;Could the Site Be Declared a Disaster to Garner Emergency Funding?
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes—and it may be overdue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the underground fire breaches the radioactive zone, this could trigger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airborne radioactive particulate release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contamination of the Missouri River watershed, a major source of drinking water, agriculture, and shipping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evacuations, health crises, and long-term land value collapse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;federal-emergency-pathways&#34;&gt;Federal Emergency Pathways:
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stafford Act Declaration&lt;/strong&gt;: If the situation worsens, Missouri’s governor could request a Presidential Disaster Declaration, unlocking FEMA funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CERCLA (Superfund) Emergency Removal Authority&lt;/strong&gt;: Already in play—but underused. It allows for fast-track action when there’s “an imminent and substantial danger to public health.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congressional Emergency Appropriations&lt;/strong&gt;: If elevated to a national infrastructure risk, Congress can pass a standalone funding bill (as was done for 9/11, Katrina, and Flint).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framing Suggestion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This isn’t just Missouri’s risk. The Missouri River touches 10 states, feeds the Mississippi, and supports the nation’s economy. If fire meets waste, it’s not just local cleanup—it’s a national emergency.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-how-could-we-possibly-contain-this-underground-fire&#34;&gt;🔥 How Could We Possibly Contain This Underground Fire?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The subsurface smoldering event (SSE) is chemically different from an open flame, but still incredibly dangerous. It&amp;rsquo;s been burning since &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-mitigation-techniques&#34;&gt;Current Mitigation Techniques:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isolation barriers&lt;/strong&gt;: A physical wall of clay and grout was installed to block migration toward the radioactive zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gas extraction wells&lt;/strong&gt;: To relieve pressure and reduce flammable methane buildup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature and gas monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: To track fire behavior in real time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-potential-measures&#34;&gt;Additional Potential Measures:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inert gas injection&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. nitrogen or CO₂) to starve oxygen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excavation + extinguishment&lt;/strong&gt; in cooler areas (very risky, rarely done)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cryogenic cooling zones&lt;/strong&gt; to create artificial cold firebreaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️ &lt;strong&gt;Limitation&lt;/strong&gt;: None of these are permanent fixes. The fire is in a chemically complex landfill.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Solution?&lt;/strong&gt; Excavation + reclamation is the only way to permanently eliminate the long-term fire-and-waste interaction risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-how-long-could-the-waste-power-us&#34;&gt;⚡ How Long Could the Waste Power Us?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an exciting part of the story: &lt;em&gt;what we once buried could power us for decades—if we reprocess it properly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-in-west-lake&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in West Lake?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mostly &lt;strong&gt;low-enriched uranium&lt;/strong&gt; and byproducts from &lt;strong&gt;WWII-era uranium refining&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While not reactor-grade today, it contains &lt;strong&gt;recoverable uranium isotopes (U-238)&lt;/strong&gt;, useful in fast reactors or molten salt reactors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exact tonnage is uncertain due to poor 1970s record-keeping, but estimates suggest &lt;strong&gt;hundreds of tons&lt;/strong&gt; of uranium-contaminated soil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rough-calculation-conservative-estimate&#34;&gt;Rough Calculation (Conservative Estimate):
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s say &lt;strong&gt;300 tons&lt;/strong&gt; of uranium-contaminated material, of which &lt;strong&gt;0.7% is usable uranium&lt;/strong&gt; (~2.1 tons of U)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A modern &lt;strong&gt;1GW reactor uses ~20 tons&lt;/strong&gt; of enriched uranium annually&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Molten salt reactors&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;SMRs&lt;/strong&gt; (Small Modular Reactors) can run on reprocessed fuel with far greater efficiency (sometimes &lt;strong&gt;2–5x longer fuel cycles&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;with-efficient-reprocessing-and-modular-use-west-lake-uranium-could&#34;&gt;With efficient reprocessing and modular use, West Lake uranium could:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuel a &lt;strong&gt;small 100MW reactor for 10–15 years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide &lt;strong&gt;proof-of-concept material&lt;/strong&gt; for a national waste-to-energy pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save &lt;strong&gt;hundreds of millions&lt;/strong&gt; in imported fuel and disposal costs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; It won’t power Missouri forever—but it could launch the &lt;strong&gt;first regenerative reactor hub&lt;/strong&gt; in the U.S., demonstrating that &lt;strong&gt;waste → wealth is real.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-we-know-that&#34;&gt;How Do We Know That?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DOE Fuel Cycle Reports&lt;/strong&gt; show reprocessing potential of low-enriched uranium in waste stockpiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;France’s &lt;strong&gt;La Hague facility&lt;/strong&gt; has reprocessed &lt;strong&gt;34,000+ tons&lt;/strong&gt; of spent fuel with &lt;strong&gt;95% recyclability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New U.S. &lt;strong&gt;thorium&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;molten salt reactor&lt;/strong&gt; designs aim to use “nuclear waste” as fuel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ORNL&lt;/strong&gt; (Oak Ridge National Lab) and &lt;strong&gt;INL&lt;/strong&gt; (Idaho National Lab) have conducted tests on &lt;strong&gt;uranium recovery from legacy waste streams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Even legacy uranium materials can be reprocessed with next-gen technology to yield usable fuel for SMRs.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
— &lt;strong&gt;Department of Energy Briefing, 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What It Would Take&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning West Lake into a model for nuclear reclamation and clean energy isn’t science fiction—it’s project management. It will take leadership, investment, and community trust. But it can be done. Here&amp;rsquo;s how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏗️ 1. The Process: What Reclamation Looks Like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Immediate Site Stabilization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accelerate the containment of the underground fire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install physical barriers to prevent migration toward radioactive waste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expand air and groundwater monitoring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Regulatory &amp;amp; Feasibility Assessments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conduct updated environmental impact reports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluate soil composition, uranium levels, and fire risk zones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop a site-specific reprocessing and modular energy plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Community Engagement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold town halls, publish reports in plain language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Form an oversight board with local representatives, scientists, and tribal/state/federal appointees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 4: Facility Construction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build an on-site reprocessing center + modular reactor facility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use existing road access + federal land where possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure labor through union partnerships and workforce development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 5: Reprocessing + Energy Integration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reclaim uranium from soil for fuel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power Missouri’s smart grid with clean, on-site nuclear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Store waste products in sealed, monitored, retrievable formats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 6: Long-Term Economic Growth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintain facility as energy and innovation hub&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attract clean-tech startups, research institutions, and workforce housing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🧾 2. Who Needs to Approve It?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a federal–state–local partnership, with clear roles and levers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stakeholder	Role&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. EPA	Must approve remediation plan and permit facility
U.S. DOE	Potential partner in advanced nuclear technology + funding
NRC (Nuclear Regulatory Commission)	Regulates nuclear facility design, waste handling
State of Missouri (DNR, Public Service Commission)	Environmental compliance, grid integration
Local governments + municipalities	Zoning, public hearings, emergency services
Congressional delegation	Can push for pilot funding and policy incentives
Public	Final arbiter of trust—must be engaged, informed, and heard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💰 3. How Much Would It Cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase	Estimated Cost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site containment + monitoring	$50–100 million
Environmental + engineering studies	$25–40 million
Facility design + approval process	$50 million
Construction (reprocessing + modular reactor)	$500–750 million
Ongoing operation + workforce development	$50+ million/year (with offsetting energy revenue)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total launch cost: ~$700M to $1B
Comparable to a stadium project or small highway expansion
Potential return: Clean energy, tech jobs, federal grants, national prestige&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📆 4. Timeline: From Fire Risk to Future Hub&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase	Timeframe	Outcome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediate stabilization	6–12 months	Reduced fire risk, restored public trust
Studies &amp;amp; approvals	1–2 years	Environmental clearance, design ready
Construction	2–3 years	Facility, reactor, and grid integration
Reprocessing &amp;amp; grid tie-in	Year 4	Energy begins flowing, soil reclamation underway
Full benefits realized	5–10 years	Jobs, innovation cluster, environmental turnaround&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community benefits—jobs, clean-up, investment—begin as early as Year 1 with stabilization and continue scaling up through construction and operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔁 5. Sustaining It Long-Term&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re not just fixing a problem—we’re building a future-proof ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustainability mechanisms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy sold to Missouri utilities and clean-tech partners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federal grants and climate tech investment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training pipeline from local high schools, trade schools, and universities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Export of expertise to other cleanup sites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a one-time fix. It becomes part of Missouri’s economic identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅ Summary: A Roadmap to Renewal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: ~$1B, mostly frontloaded, with long-term ROI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jobs: Begin immediately, with permanent roles by Year 3–4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approvals: Federal + state + local partnership, with public trust essential&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timeline: 6 months to stabilize, 5 years to fully launch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outcome: Missouri becomes a national model for turning waste into wealth&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Nuclear Energy Future</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/nuclear-energy-future/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 14:03:58 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/nuclear-energy-future/</guid>
        <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;title: &amp;ldquo;Transforming Our Power Grid with Advanced Nuclear Technology&amp;rdquo; date: 2025-06-18 description: &amp;ldquo;Exploring the future of clean energy through the integration of MSRs, SMRs, and Fast Neutron Reactors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Future of Energy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the world seeks cleaner, more sustainable energy solutions, advanced nuclear technologies are poised to revolutionize our power grid. By combining the safety and efficiency of molten salt reactors (MSRs), the flexibility and scalability of small modular reactors (SMRs), and the innovative potential of fast neutron reactors, we can pave the way for a cleaner, healthier, and more sustainable energy future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website explores how these cutting-edge technologies can transform our energy landscape. By reducing pollution, revitalizing our land, and providing cleaner, reliable energy, we can foster a better quality of life and ensure a sustainable future for generations to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-vision-for-west-lake-powering-the-future-from-the-past&#34;&gt;A Vision for West Lake: Powering the Future from the Past
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine standing at the edge of the West Lake Landfill—not as a site of contamination, but as a hub of innovation. A small cluster of next-generation energy systems hums in the distance. These aren’t your grandfather’s nuclear reactors. They’re molten salt small modular reactors (SMRs), built to safely and efficiently run on fuel recovered from the very waste buried here decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step one: reprocessing. Contaminated soil is sorted and treated in a secure, on-site facility. The low-grade uranium—once considered a liability—is extracted using advanced chemical separation. Instead of being buried and forgotten, it’s transformed into fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step two: clean energy. That reclaimed fuel is dissolved into molten salt and fed into modular reactors, each roughly the size of a shipping container. These units are self-regulating, inherently safe, and built to run quietly for years without refueling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power generated doesn’t just light up homes—it powers the cleanup, the research labs, the trucks, the data centers. One unit might serve an entire neighborhood. A few more could support the grid, bring down local energy costs, and attract new industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West Lake becomes a living demonstration: how legacy waste, innovation, and clean energy can work together. A site once marked by fear becomes a symbol of transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Benefits of MSRs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safety and passive cooling features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficient fuel usage and reduced waste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lower operating pressures and inherent stability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Advantages of SMRs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modularity and rapid deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lower upfront costs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideal for decentralized power grids and rural areas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast Neutron Reactors (FNRs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capable of recycling spent nuclear fuel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reduction of long-lived radioactive waste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enabling a more sustainable fuel cycle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating MSRs, SMRs, and FNRs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phased strategy starting with MSR and SMR deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure and safety systems designed for future FNR integration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redundancy and Safety Measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-loop coolant systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faraday cages and hardened electronics for EMP and solar flare resilience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battery backups, diverse power sources, and microgrid capabilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation Timeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0–5 years: Research, pilot testing (e.g., China’s TMSR-LF1), early NuScale projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5–10 years: Regulatory approvals and initial deployments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10–20 years: Widespread adoption and infrastructure growth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future Prospects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology improvements and international collaboration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public-private partnerships and global deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Vision for the Future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the not-so-distant future, the world has transformed. Cities gleam under skies clearer than ever, thanks to the clean, efficient energy provided by advanced nuclear technologies. Molten salt reactors, small modular reactors, and fast neutron reactors work in harmony, providing abundant clean energy to power homes, industries, and transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days of smog-filled air and polluted rivers. The new energy landscape has revitalized our planet, with land once scarred by fossil fuel extraction now blooming with greenery. Public health has improved dramatically, as clean air and water have become the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communities are thriving with reliable, affordable energy. The economy flourishes, driven by innovation and sustainability. This new era aligns human progress with the health of our planet, ensuring a bright, sustainable future for generations to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>West Lake: A Vision for Clean Power</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/west-lake-a-vivision-for-clean-powerr/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 17:40:02 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/west-lake-a-vivision-for-clean-powerr/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;west-lake-a-vision-for-clean-power&#34;&gt;West Lake: A Vision for Clean Power
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-waste-to-energy&#34;&gt;From Waste to Energy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine standing at the edge of the West Lake Landfill—not as a site of contamination, but as a hub of innovation. A small cluster of next-generation energy systems hums in the distance.
These aren’t your grandfather’s nuclear reactors. They’re molten salt small modular reactors (SMRs), built to safely and efficiently run on fuel recovered from the very waste buried here decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reprocessing-the-past&#34;&gt;Reprocessing the Past
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process begins with on-site reprocessing. Contaminated soil is sorted and treated in a secure facility. Low-grade uranium is separated using advanced chemical methods. What was once buried and feared is now reclaimed as fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clean-modular-energy&#34;&gt;Clean, Modular Energy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reclaimed uranium is dissolved into molten salt and loaded into modular reactors—each about the size of a shipping container. These units are self-regulating, inherently safe, and capable of running for years with minimal maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reactor could power a neighborhood. Several could serve the entire region, including cleanup operations and research labs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;economic-revival-through-innovation&#34;&gt;Economic Revival Through Innovation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reprocessing facility alone would bring high-skill jobs to the area—chemists, engineers, welders, safety officers. Building and maintaining the reactors would support steady employment for local workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with stable, affordable energy, West Lake could attract clean tech startups, labs, and manufacturers. This isn’t just cleanup—it’s economic revival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-safer-empowered-community&#34;&gt;A Safer, Empowered Community
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, the community surrounding West Lake has lived with uncertainty. This vision flips that narrative. With transparent monitoring and community access to safety data, trust and pride can be restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partnering with schools and colleges, the site could become a learning hub, inspiring the next generation to lead in energy and environmental stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-action&#34;&gt;Take Action
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;West Lake doesn’t have to remain a symbol of fear. It can become a model for responsible innovation, clean energy, and community empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share this vision. Start the conversation. Support local efforts to make it real.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-more&#34;&gt;Learn More
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;Background on the West Lake Landfill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;How Molten Salt Reactors Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;SMRs and the Future of Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;Community Resources and Safety Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Rethinking Energy and Nuclear Waste: From West Lake to Future Solutions</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/rethinking-energy/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/rethinking-energy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;rethinking-energy-and-nuclear-waste&#34;&gt;Rethinking Energy and Nuclear Waste
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post outlines a wide-ranging discussion exploring the legacy of nuclear waste at the West Lake Landfill, the potential of Small Modular Reactors (SMRs), and alternative energy concepts including solar thermal mass storage and bladeless wind turbine networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-west-lake-landfill-a-legacy-problem&#34;&gt;1. The West Lake Landfill: A Legacy Problem
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Near St. Louis, Missouri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue:&lt;/strong&gt; Contains radioactive waste from WWII-era Manhattan Project uranium processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; Proximity to an underground fire and nearby neighborhoods raises ongoing health and environmental concerns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbolism:&lt;/strong&gt; Represents a broader pattern of short-term nuclear decisions with long-term consequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-the-scale-of-nuclear-infrastructure&#34;&gt;2. The Scale of Nuclear Infrastructure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Model:&lt;/strong&gt; Centralized, large-scale nuclear power plants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely high cost and long construction timelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safety concerns due to catastrophic failure risks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficult public perception and trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex waste management and regulatory oversight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-small-modular-reactors-smrs&#34;&gt;3. Small Modular Reactors (SMRs)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; Compact, factory-built nuclear reactors designed for safer, distributed power generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passive safety systems that reduce meltdown risks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalability — modular design allows for flexible deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to utilize alternative fuels like thorium or reprocessed plutonium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role:&lt;/strong&gt; A promising transition technology bridging the gap between fossil fuels and long-term clean energy sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-alternative-energy-concepts&#34;&gt;4. Alternative Energy Concepts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-solar-thermal-mass-storage&#34;&gt;A. Solar Thermal Mass Storage
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Use concentrated solar energy to heat dense material such as stone or brick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magnifying lenses or mirrors focus sunlight onto a heat-retaining core&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thermal mass is insulated with sand to minimize heat loss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stored heat used to drive a steam turbine and generate electricity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renewable and low-tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful in off-grid or remote environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can store energy for nighttime or cloudy days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b-bladeless-wind-turbine-networks&#34;&gt;B. Bladeless Wind Turbine Networks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design:&lt;/strong&gt; Use oscillating vertical structures instead of traditional blades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt; Power generated through vortex-induced vibrations or piezoelectric materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quieter and safer for wildlife and humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to maintain due to fewer moving parts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideal for urban, suburban, or modular rural installations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability:&lt;/strong&gt; Can operate in networked swarms, adjusting orientation or load dynamically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-final-reflections&#34;&gt;5. Final Reflections
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From toxic waste in landfills to the promise of modular nuclear and renewable networks, the future of energy depends on choices we make now. We need a multi-pronged strategy that addresses old mistakes while investing in forward-thinking solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let the failures buried in our land guide us toward the energy systems we deserve above it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Effortless</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/effortless/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 16:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/effortless/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was effortless—
and yet, you made me want to.
Want to rise, to bloom, to rupture.
Not because I had to—
but because you saw me like no one else ever did.
And in that gaze, I remembered I was still becoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember a hum.
A glow.
Not loud, not lit—just&amp;hellip; resonant.
The kind of frequency two souls find
when the world falls quiet enough to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my family sees it.
They don’t always understand what they’re looking at,
but I think they know there’s something
smoldering just beneath the skin.
A tremor. A pull.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still—
I feel like I’m finishing my transition into a black hole.
Collapsed brilliance.
Too heavy with memory to burn.
Too quiet to scream.
And yet still pulling everything inward—
light included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I aspire to be alone.
Not because I don’t love—
I do.
But maybe because I fear I’d be a barrier
to someone else’s bliss.
Because I can’t deliver.
Because I am selfish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want peace and fire.
Blood and lust.
I crave your presence,
like a starving god craves incense and trembling hands.
Love requited through your beauty and spirit alone.
No obligations. Just knowing.
Just the echo of my name in your breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss feeling connected.
Miss that tether.
Miss being consumed—
not out of need,
but out of holy hunger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to find our note—
that secret, sacred tone that only we could hear—
and fuck it for hours.
Worship it.
Let it burn through the silence
until we forget where I end and you begin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>2025-06-05 Workout</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/planet-fitness-workout/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/planet-fitness-workout/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-planet-fitness-workout&#34;&gt;💪 Planet Fitness Workout
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;warm-up&#34;&gt;Warm-up
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 min treadmill&lt;/strong&gt; – Squat walk at &lt;strong&gt;12 incline, speed 5.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-circuit-20-min-total&#34;&gt;Main Circuit (20 min total)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rotate through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Squat walks&lt;/strong&gt; – deep squat position, walking forward/backward while staying low&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low bear crawls&lt;/strong&gt; – hips low, core engaged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tricep dips&lt;/strong&gt; – using bench or platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medicine ball slams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunges&lt;/strong&gt; – alternating legs, controlled form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light yoga / deep stretches&lt;/strong&gt; – hip openers, spinal twists, hamstring/quad stretches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cardio-push&#34;&gt;Cardio Push
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 min treadmill run&lt;/strong&gt; – Incline 4, speed 6.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 min walk&lt;/strong&gt; – cooldown pace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;grip-finisher&#34;&gt;Grip Finisher
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 min dead hang&lt;/strong&gt; from pull-up bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Power Lunch: Peanut Butter, Banana &amp; Spices</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/powerhousesandwhich/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/powerhousesandwhich/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;power-sandwich-peanut-butter-banana--spices&#34;&gt;Power Sandwich: Peanut Butter, Banana &amp;amp; Spices
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This sandwich packs a punch—perfect for lunch or pre-workout fuel. It’s rich in healthy fats, natural sugars, fiber, and anti-inflammatory ingredients. Balanced, energizing, and seriously satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-ingredients&#34;&gt;🥪 Ingredients
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 slices whole wheat bread&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbsp natural peanut butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp local honey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp chia seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;½ medium banana, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;¼ tsp ground turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinch of black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;¼ tsp Ceylon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-it-works&#34;&gt;🧠 Why It Works
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peanut butter&lt;/strong&gt; – Healthy fats and protein for satiety and muscle support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chia seeds&lt;/strong&gt; – Omega-3s, fiber, and slow-digesting carbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Banana&lt;/strong&gt; – Natural energy and potassium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turmeric + pepper&lt;/strong&gt; – Anti-inflammatory duo (pepper boosts turmeric absorption)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ceylon cinnamon&lt;/strong&gt; – Helps regulate blood sugar and adds a warm spice kick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local honey&lt;/strong&gt; – Antioxidants and allergy-friendly support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-nutrition-estimate&#34;&gt;🔬 Nutrition Estimate
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Nutrient&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Amount&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Calories&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~463 kcal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Protein&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~14–16g&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Fat&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~27g&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Carbs&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~40–45g&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Fiber&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~9–11g&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Sugars&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~10–12g&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-pro-tip&#34;&gt;💡 Pro Tip
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try toasting the bread for crunch, or batch-prep a whipped peanut butter spread with cinnamon, turmeric, and honey for the week. Just stir and store in a jar!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;draft: true&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuel your goals, one bite at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Overnight Oats</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/my-overnight-oats/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 14:25:56 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/my-overnight-oats/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;quick-and-easy-breakfast&#34;&gt;Quick and Easy Breakfast
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best way to start your day is with a dense nutrient bomb at the beginning of the day. Something with plenty of healthy fats, fiber, antioxidants, and slow-digesting carbohydrates — all working together to fuel your body and mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This overnight oat blend is more than just convenient — it&amp;rsquo;s a powerful, balanced meal designed to nourish your gut, support your brain, and stabilize your energy levels throughout the day. It&amp;rsquo;s packed with omega-3s from walnuts and chia seeds, rich in fiber and resistant starch from oats, and loaded with anti-inflammatory compounds like turmeric and blueberries. The combination of protein, fat, and complex carbs helps prevent blood sugar spikes and crashes, keeping you fuller longer and helping you stay sharp and focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re lifting weights, walking into meetings, or chasing dreams, this breakfast sets you up to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;estimated-nutritional-value-per-8oz-jar&#34;&gt;Estimated Nutritional Value (per 8oz jar)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Nutrient&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Amount per jar&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;% Daily Value (based on 2,000 cal diet)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~380–430 kcal&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~19–22%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~15–17 g&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~30–34%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~12–14 g&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~43–50%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthy Fats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~19–21 g&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~29–32%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Omega-3 (ALA)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~4 g&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&amp;gt;250% (more than daily recommended)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magnesium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~130–160 mg&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~33–40%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zinc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~2–3 mg&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~20–25%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~3–4 mg&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~17–22%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potassium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~450–550 mg&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~10–15%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manganese&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~1.5–2 mg&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~65–100%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niacin (B3)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~1 mg&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~6–8%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antioxidants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;High (from berries, turmeric, nuts)&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Excellent for cellular health&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;draft: true&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Ingredient&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Amount&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Why It’s Included&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/product/protein-oats&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein Oats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;½ cup&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;High-protein whole grain carbs for long-lasting energy and fullness&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/organic-chia-seeds.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chia Seeds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 tbsp&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Omega-3s, fiber, and a gelatinous texture that aids digestion&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/organic-pumpkin-seeds.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pumpkin Seeds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 tbsp&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Rich in magnesium, zinc, and healthy fats for heart and immune support&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/blog/healthy-living/baking-with-nuts/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walnuts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 tbsp (crushed)&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Plant-based omega-3s and polyphenols to reduce inflammation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/blog/healthy-living/blueberries-10-reasons-you-should-eat-them/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blueberries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;¼ cup&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Antioxidants to fight oxidative stress and boost brain health&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/flaked-coconut.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coconut Flakes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 tbsp&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Healthy fats and texture; supports metabolism and adds flavor&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pb2foods.com/products/pb2-original-powdered-peanut-butter-peanut-butter-powder&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;PB2 (Powdered Peanut Butter)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 tbsp&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Protein and flavor with less fat and fewer calories than traditional peanut butter&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/blog/healthy-living/turmeric-benefits-recipes/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turmeric&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;¼ tsp&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/blog/healthy-living/how-to-use-black-pepper/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Pepper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;A pinch&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Enhances absorption of curcumin in turmeric&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/blog/healthy-living/oat-milk-how-to-make-it/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oat Milk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;½ cup&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Dairy-free creamy base with added fiber&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bobsredmill.com/blog/healthy-living/baking-with-natural-sweeteners/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maple Syrup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 tsp (optional)&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Natural sweetener with trace minerals — better than refined sugar&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;supplies&#34;&gt;Supplies
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6–12 8oz Mason jars (with lids)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
