<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Nuclear on Charles Lewer</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/tags/nuclear/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Nuclear on Charles Lewer</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 17:40:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/tags/nuclear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>West Lake: A Vision for Clean Power</title>
        <link>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/west-lake-a-vivision-for-clean-powerr/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 17:40:02 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cd-lewer.github.io/hub/post/west-lake-a-vivision-for-clean-powerr/</guid>
        <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;draft-false&#34;&gt;title: &amp;ldquo;West Lake: A Vision for Clean Power&amp;rdquo;
date: 2025-06-17
draft: false
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;west-lake-a-vision-for-clean-power&#34;&gt;West Lake: A Vision for Clean Power
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-waste-to-energy&#34;&gt;From Waste to Energy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine standing at the edge of the West Lake Landfill—not as a site of contamination, but as a hub of innovation. A small cluster of next-generation energy systems hums in the distance.
These aren’t your grandfather’s nuclear reactors. They’re molten salt small modular reactors (SMRs), built to safely and efficiently run on fuel recovered from the very waste buried here decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reprocessing-the-past&#34;&gt;Reprocessing the Past
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process begins with on-site reprocessing. Contaminated soil is sorted and treated in a secure facility. Low-grade uranium is separated using advanced chemical methods. What was once buried and feared is now reclaimed as fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clean-modular-energy&#34;&gt;Clean, Modular Energy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reclaimed uranium is dissolved into molten salt and loaded into modular reactors—each about the size of a shipping container. These units are self-regulating, inherently safe, and capable of running for years with minimal maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reactor could power a neighborhood. Several could serve the entire region, including cleanup operations and research labs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;economic-revival-through-innovation&#34;&gt;Economic Revival Through Innovation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reprocessing facility alone would bring high-skill jobs to the area—chemists, engineers, welders, safety officers. Building and maintaining the reactors would support steady employment for local workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with stable, affordable energy, West Lake could attract clean tech startups, labs, and manufacturers. This isn’t just cleanup—it’s economic revival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-safer-empowered-community&#34;&gt;A Safer, Empowered Community
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, the community surrounding West Lake has lived with uncertainty. This vision flips that narrative. With transparent monitoring and community access to safety data, trust and pride can be restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partnering with schools and colleges, the site could become a learning hub, inspiring the next generation to lead in energy and environmental stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-action&#34;&gt;Take Action
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;West Lake doesn’t have to remain a symbol of fear. It can become a model for responsible innovation, clean energy, and community empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share this vision. Start the conversation. Support local efforts to make it real.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-more&#34;&gt;Learn More
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;Background on the West Lake Landfill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;How Molten Salt Reactors Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;SMRs and the Future of Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#&#34; &gt;Community Resources and Safety Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
